Guide to the Mediterranean Pilgrimage Association photograph album from the Hisham Khatib Collection AD.MC.030_ref150
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Mediterranean Pilgrimage Association - Hisham Khatib Collection
1928
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
AD.MC.030_ref150
131 Leaves - One album containing postcards, tourism booklets, tickets and a cruise itinerary and berthing list.
Generally good, some brittle and warped.
The Mediterranean Pilgrimage Association album contains postcards from a cruise on the S.S. Umbria (SITMAR line – Societa Italiana di Servizi Marittimi) that left London on the 27th April 1928. The postcards are mainly from Egypt, Palestine and Turkey. The Hisham Khatib Collection on the Holy Land and region is one of the largest collections of Middle Eastern photography still in private hands. It contains hundreds of 19th century original albumen photographic prints as well as many travel albums of the same period and early 20th century with hundreds of black and white photographs and postcards. The collection contains photography from dozens of photographers, but the albumen prints are mostly the work of the Bonfils family, Francis Frith, Francis Bedford, Matson photo Service, American Colony, Zangaki Brothers, and Frank Mason Good. Dr. Hisham Khatib has spent over 40 years amassing a vast and historically valuable collection of representations of the Near East, including the Holy Lands, including Palestine, Jordan, Turkey, Syria and Egypt. The artworks in this extraordinary collection include paintings, prints, maps, books, photographs, as well as postcards. A large part of Dr. Khatib's collection consists of rare photographic prints: he has over 3,000 images. See main collection http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/akkasah/ad_mc_030/
Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150
Content Description
The Mediterranean Pilgrimage Association album contains postcards from a cruise on the S.S. Umbria (SITMAR line – Societa Italiana di Servizi Marittimi) that left London on the 27th April 1928. The postcards are mainly from Egypt, Palestine and Turkey.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Palestine; Egypt; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Postcards; Turkey; Travel
- Mediterranean Pilgrimage Association
  - Front cover, Circa 1928; ref150_000001; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards
  - Inside cover: Boat plan, berthing list and sample menu from the Mediterranean Pilgrimage Association cruise on the S.S. Umbria, SITMAR line - Societa Italiana di Servizi Marittimi., 27 April 1928; ref150_000002; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Boats/Ships; Food; Advertisements; Newspaper Clippings; English Writing; Italian Writing; Freemasonry; London, England, UK; Italy; Egypt; Palestine; Turkey; Greece; France
  - (blank page), Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000003; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
  - Tram Services and Excursions from Parker's Hotel, Naples., Circa 1928; ref150_000004; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    English Writing; French Writing; Advertisements; Transportation; Hotels; Trams; Museums; Naples (Italy); Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Printed Materials
  - Map of Naples from Parkers Hotel and Entrance Ticket to Solfatara., April 1928; ref150_000005; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Naples (Italy); English Writing; Maps; Italian Writing; Hotels; Advertisements; Printed Materials
  - Advertisement for L. La Duca & C. Catania., 1927; ref150_000006; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Advertisements; Italian Writing; English Writing; Catania, Italy; Transportation; Printed Materials
  - Postcard of the elephant and obelisk in Catania., Circa 1927; ref150_000007; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Elephants; Animals; Fountains; Statues/Sculptures; Postcards; Photographic Prints; Catania, Italy; Monuments/Memorials
  - Postcards of the lighthouse and Ras-el-Tin Palace in Alexandria., Circa 1928; ref150_000008; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Lighthouses; Buildings; Architecture; Seas; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Alexandria, Egypt; English Writing; Mediterranean Sea; Photographic Prints; Palaces; Ras El Tin Palace
  - Two postcards of Alexandria harbour., Circa 1928; ref150_000009; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Individual Portraits; Men; Hats; Alexandria, Egypt; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Seas; Ports; Mediterranean Sea; English Writing
  - Two postcards of Mohamed Ali Square and the French Gardens, Alexandria., Circa 1928; ref150_000010; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; English Writing; Alexandria, Egypt; Carriages/Coaches; Buildings; Architecture; Palm Trees; Men; Animals; Horses; Regional/National Dress; Streets/Roads; Transportation; Architecture; Buildings; Gardens; Street Lamps
  - Postcards of the Majestic Hotel and general view of Alexandria., Circa 1928; ref150_000011; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; English Writing; Alexandria, Egypt; Gardens; Buildings; Architecture; Men; Women; Palm Trees; Streets/Roads; Hotels
  - Postcards of the El Nabi Daniel Mosque and Fort Napoleon in Alexandria., Circa 1928; ref150_000012; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; English Writing; Alexandria, Egypt; Forts/Castles; Buildings; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Men; Women; Regional/National Dress; Carriages/Coaches; Children; Street Vendors; Shops; Mosques; Religious Sites; Nabi Daniel Mosque; Hats; Fez/Tarboush
  - Postcards of the railway station and Nubar Pasha monument in Alexandria., Circa 1928; ref150_000013; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; English Writing; Alexandria, Egypt; Buildings; Architecture; Railways; Men; Street Lamps; French Writing; Clocks/Watches; Statues/Sculptures; Monuments/Memorials; Pasha; Advertisements; Nubar Pasha (Nubar Nubarian), 1825-1899
  - A postcard of Sherif Pasha Street in Alexandria., Circa 1928; ref150_000014; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Architecture; Alexandria, Egypt; Streets/Roads; Men; Women; Buildings; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; English Writing; Shops; Street Lamps
  - Postcards of the Antoniades Garden and general view of Alexandria., Circa 1928; ref150_000015; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; English Writing; Alexandria, Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Individual Portraits; Outdoors; Men; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Buildings; Gardens; Parks; Palm Trees; Architecture
  - A postcard of the San Stefano Hotel and Ramleh Casino in Alexandria., Circa 1928; ref150_000016; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Tennis; Sports; English Writing; Hotels; Casinos; Buildings; Architecture; Palm Trees; San Stefano, Alexandria, Egypt; Flags; Cars/Trucks; Transportation
  - Postcards of the Alexandria Exchange and El Mahmoudiyah canal., Circa 1928; ref150_000017; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Architecture; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Carriages/Coaches; Alexandria, Egypt; Clocks/Watches; Men; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Street Lamps; English Writing; French Writing; Arabic Writing; Regional/National Dress; Canals; Water; Turbans
  - Postcards of Mohammed Ali Square and Pompey's Pillar in Alexandria., Circa 1928; ref150_000018; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Carriages/Coaches; Streets/Roads; Alexandria, Egypt; Monuments/Memorials; Men; Buildings; Architecture; English Writing; Palm Trees; French Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Statues/Sculptures; Transportation
  - (Blank page), Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000019; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
  - Postcards of the Nubar Pasha monument and panoramic view of Alexandria., Circa 1928; ref150_000020; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Alexandria, Egypt; Statues/Sculptures; Buildings; Architecture; Parks; English Writing; Men; Monuments/Memorials; Nubar Pasha (Nubar Nubarian), 1825-1899
  - Two postcards of Cairo., Circa 1928; ref150_000021; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Cairo, Egypt; Cemeteries; Buildings; Architecture; English Writing; Mosques; Religious Sites; Monuments/Memorials; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt
  - Postcards of the interior of a Coptic church and Mamluk tombs in Cairo., Circa 1928; ref150_000022; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; English Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Tombs/Mausoleums; Churches; Religious Sites; Monuments/Memorials; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Imagery; Men; Turbans; Regional/National Dress; Saint Virgin Mary's Coptic Orthodox Church (Hanging Church); Cemeteries
  - Postcards of tombs of the Caliphs, an obelisk and street scene in Cairo., Circa 1928; ref150_000023; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Monuments/Memorials; Tombs/Mausoleums; Cairo, Egypt; Transportation; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; Animals; Horses; Carriages/Coaches; Buildings; Architecture; Group Portraits; Outdoors; Men; English Writing; Cemeteries; Cattle/Cows; Women; Donkeys; Religious Sites; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Postcards of the Blue Mosque and Citadel in Cairo., Circa 1928; ref150_000024; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt; Cairo, Egypt; Forts/Castles; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Animals; Donkeys; Men; Children; Regional/National Dress; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha; Street Lamps
  - Three postcards of Cairo., Circa 1928; ref150_000025; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Cairo, Egypt; Forts/Castles; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt; Religious Sites; Mosques; Streets/Roads; Animals; Donkeys; Nile River; Palm Trees; Rivers; Buildings; Architecture; Men; Children; Regional/National Dress; Pyramids; Monuments/Memorials; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha; Giza, Egypt
  - A Postcard of the statue of Ibrahim Pacha and the Khedivial Opera House in Opera Square, Cairo., Circa 1928; ref150_000026; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; English Writing; Statues/Sculptures; Monuments/Memorials; Buildings; Architecture; Street Lamps; Streets/Roads; Animals; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Ataba, Cairo, Egypt; Pasha; Theater; Ibrahim, Pasha, 1789-1848
  - Two postcards of the Sphinx and Pyramids in Giza., Circa 1928; ref150_000027; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; English Writing; Giza, Egypt; Pyramids; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Men; Regional/National Dress; Animals; Camels; Monuments/Memorials; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Two postcards of the Sphinx and Pyramids in Giza., Circa 1928; ref150_000028; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Giza, Egypt; Pyramids; Monuments/Memorials; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Individual Portraits; Outdoors; Men; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Animals; Camels; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Two postcards and newspaper clipping of the Sphinx and the Pyramids, Giza., Circa 1928; ref150_000029; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Giza, Egypt; Pyramids; Monuments/Memorials; English Writing; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Two postcards of the Pyramids of Giza., Circa 1928; ref150_000030; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Giza, Egypt; Palm Trees; Pyramids; Monuments/Memorials; Men; Children; Animals; Camels; Buildings; Architecture; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Postcards of Kasr el Nil bridge and the Pyramids., Circa 1928; ref150_000031; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Giza, Egypt; Cairo, Egypt; Palm Trees; Monuments/Memorials; Pyramids; Bridges; Animals; Camels; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Men; Turbans; Regional/National Dress; Nile River; Rivers; English Writing; Statues/Sculptures; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Postcards of the barracks at Kasr el Nil and a wedding., Circa 1928; ref150_000032; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; English Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Women; Nile River; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Rivers; Animals; Camels; Men; Turbans; Regional/National Dress; Buildings; Weddings; Military/Soldiers
  - Postcards of Al Azhar University and a coffee house in Cairo., Circa 1928; ref150_000033; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; English Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Group Portraits; Tea/Coffee; Turbans; Regional/National Dress; Students; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Buildings; Hats; Universities; Al Azhar University/Jāmiʻat al-Azhar; Restaurants/bars; Teachers; Schools/Education
  - Postcards of the Holy Carpet (Mahmal) procession and the pyramids., Circa 1928; ref150_000034; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Cairo, Egypt; Giza, Egypt; Pyramids; Animals; Camels; Men; Boys; Children; Monuments/Memorials; Nile River; Rivers; English Writing; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Mosque-Madrassa of Sultan Hassan; Parades/Processions; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Postcards of men working on a shadoof and the statue of Ramesses II in Memphis., Circa 1928; ref150_000035; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Men; Boys; Children; Cairo, Egypt; Statues/Sculptures; Workers; Hats; Palm Trees; English Writing; Irrigation; Water; Memphis, Egypt; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Postcards of women and children and the interior of the Mosque of Mohamed Ali., Circa 1928; ref150_000036; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Children; Regional/National Dress; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Girls; English Writing; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha; Boys; Cairo, Egypt
  - Map of the Nile River., Circa 1928; ref150_000037; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Maps; Nile River; Rivers; English Writing; Mediterranean Sea; Deserts; Egypt; Printed Materials
  - (Blank page), Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000038; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
  - Postcard of a Nile Steamer named 'Arabia' approaching Aswan., Circa 1928; ref150_000039; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Nile River; Rivers; Buildings; Landscapes; Aswan, Egypt; Postcards; Flags; Mountains/Hills
  - Postcard of the Tomb of Tutankhamen., Circa 1928; ref150_000040; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; English Writing; Thebes, Egypt; Men; Doors/Entrances; Tombs/Mausoleums; Monuments/Memorials; Postcards; Luxor, Egypt; Uniforms; Police; Religious Sites; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Postcards of Jerusalem., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000041; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; English Writing; Streets/Roads; French Writing; Spanish Writing; Italian Writing; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Buildings; Individual Portraits; Animals; Postcards; Jerusalem; Palestine; Umbrellas/Parasols; Railways
  - Three postcards of monuments in Jerusalem., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000042; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; French Writing; English Writing; Spanish Writing; Italian Writing; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Buildings; Architecture; Chandeliers; Religious Sites; Churches; Gethsemane, Jerusalem; Jerusalem; Palestine; Caves
  - A postcard of the interior of the Church of Holy Sepulchre., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000043; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Jerusalem; Palestine; Churches; Religious Sites; Religious Imagery; Chandeliers; Architecture
  - Three postcards of the interior of the Church of Holy Sepulchre., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000044; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; English Writing; French Writing; Spanish Writing; Italian Writing; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; Religious Sites; Religious Imagery; Chandeliers; Statues/Sculptures; Architecture; Jerusalem; Palestine
  - Postcards of the Church of Holy Sepulchre and the Tower of Antonia., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000045; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Photographic Prints; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Jerusalem; Palestine; English Writing; French Writing; Italian Writing; Children; Men; Regional/National Dress; Spanish Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A postcard of the Arch of Ecce Homo., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000046; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Photographic Prints; Men; Animals; Regional/National Dress; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Sites; French Writing; English Writing; Spanish Writing; Italian Writing; Streets/Roads; Jerusalem; Palestine; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Postcards of the Dome of the Rock and the Jordan River., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000047; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Albumen Prints; Religious Sites; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Jordan; Rivers; French Writing; English Writing; Spanish Writing; Italian Writing; Men; Regional/National Dress; Horses; Architecture; Buildings; Jordan River; Animals; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf
  - Postcards of the Valley of Jehoshaphat and Al Aqsa Mosque., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000048; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Jerusalem; Palestine; Buildings; French Writing; English Writing; Spanish Writing; Italian Writing; Architecture; Al-Aqsa Mosque/al-Masjid al-ʾAqṣā; Mosques; Tomb of Absalom; Tomb of Zechariah; Tomb of Benei Hezir; Kidron Valley; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Religious Sites
  - Postcards of the Tombs of the Kings and Damascus Gate., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000049; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Jerusalem; Damascus Gate, Jerusalem; Palestine; Buildings; Architecture; Tombs/Mausoleums; French Writing; English Writing; Spanish Writing; Italian Writing; Animals; Donkeys; Men; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Religious Sites
  - Postcards of the interior of the Dome of the Rock and the Tomb of the Virgin Mary., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000050; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Jerusalem; Postcards; Albumen Prints; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Kidron Valley; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Tombs/Mausoleums; Churches; French Writing; English Writing; Spanish Writing; Italian Writing; Men; Regional/National Dress; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Palestine; Priests/Clergymen; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Church of the Sepulchre of Saint Mary/Tomb of Saint Mary
  - Postcards of the Tower of David and Hippicus, and the Golden Gate., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000051; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Tower of David/Burj Dāwūd (Jerusalem Citadel); Jerusalem; Palestine; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Monuments/Memorials; Golden Gate, Jerusalem; French Writing; English Writing; Italian Writing; Spanish Writing
  - Two postcards of the Garden of Gethsemane., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000052; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Gethsemane, Jerusalem; Gardens; Jerusalem; Palestine; French Writing; English Writing; Spanish Writing; Italian Writing; Men; Regional/National Dress; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Sites; Mountains/Hills
  - Postcards of the Church of the Pater Noster and Mount Zion., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000053; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Albumen Prints; Jerusalem; Palestine; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Churches; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Mount Zion/Jabal Sahyoun, Jerusalem; Men; Regional/National Dress; French Writing; English Writing; Spanish Writing; Italian Writing; Landscapes; Church of the Pater Noster; Chapel of the Ascension
  - Postcards of the Mount of Olives, Chapel of the Ascension, and the Cenacle., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000054; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Jerusalem; Palestine; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Religious Sites; French Writing; Italian Writing; Spanish Writing; English Writing; Architecture; Monuments/Memorials; Chapel of the Ascension; Mountains/Hills
  - Postcards of the Abbey of the Dormition and Ein Karem., Circa 1900-1928; ref150_000055; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    Postcards; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Palestine; Religious Sites; Churches; Buildings; Architecture; Mount Zion/Jabal Sahyoun, Jerusalem; French Writing; English Writing; Spanish Writing; Men; Italian Writing; Ein Karem, Jerusalem; Landscapes
  - Booklet entitled "The Threshold of the Judgement Gate on the Place of the Russian Excavations in Jerusalem", 1927; ref150_000056; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    - Front cover of a booklet entitled "The Threshold of the Judgement Gate on the Place of the Russian Excavations in Jerusalem (Compiled upon works of Archemandrite Antonine, B. P. Mansourov and V. N. Khitrovo)", 1927; ref150_000056a; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
      Books; English Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Printed Materials
    - Booklet entitled "The Threshold of the Judgement Gate on the Place of the Russian Excavations in Jerusalem", 1927; ref150_000056b; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
      Books; English Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Printed Materials
    - Booklet entitled "The Threshold of the Judgement Gate on the Place of the Russian Excavations in Jerusalem", 1927; ref150_000056c; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
    - Booklet entitled "The Threshold of the Judgement Gate on the Place of the Russian Excavations in Jerusalem", 1927; ref150_000056d; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ad_mc_030_ref150)
      Books; Jerusalem; English Writing; Palestine; Printed Materials